Guide to the CITA records, 1991-2012.
CITA records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
CITA records, 1991-2012.
8532
CITA (Centro Independiente de Trabajadores Agricolas)
5.5 cubic feet.
Reports, photographs, digital media.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Reports, Board of Directors records, subject files, audits, photographs, DVDs and CDs documenting CITA.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
CITA, or the Independent Farmworkers Center, was created in 1991, with the help of Rural and Migrant Ministry, as a grassroots farmworker membership organization. Its first office was in Florida, New York and in 2001 it moved to Albion, New York. Its main focus was to educate farmworkers about their rights and to organize workers to negotiate directly with their employers to resolve problems with work or housing.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Reports, Board of Directors records, subject files, audits, photographs, DVDs and CDs documenting CITA.
SUBJECTS
Names:
CITA (Centro Independiente de Trabajadores Agricolas); Independent Farmworkers Center.
Subjects:
Agricultural laborers -- New York State.; Migrant labor -- United States.; Migrant agricultural laborers -- United States.; Housing, Rural -- United States.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- CITA history (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Amaricans, fresh vegetables, and farm work (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Bylaws (Box 1, Folder 3)
- CITA En La Lucha (Box 1, Folder 4)
- CITA brochures (Box 1, Folder 5)
- CITA logos, clip art (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Board of directors, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Board of directors, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Board of directors, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Board of directors, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Board of directors, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Board of directors, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Board of directors, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Board of directors, 1992-2000 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Board of directors notes, 1998-2001 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Board of directors notes, 1995-1998 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Notes, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Notes, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Board orientation, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Annual membership meetings, 2002-2004 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Board of directors training, 2002-2006 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- CITA staff, 1994-2009 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Retreat, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Retreat, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Retreat, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Annual meetings, 1993-2004 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- CITA office - Albion, 2001-2008 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Personnel policies (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Job descriptions, 1996-2004 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Plans, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Plans, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Plans, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Plans, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Reports, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Reports, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Reports, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Reports, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Staff meetings, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Staff meetings, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Staff meetings, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Staff meetings, 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Farmworker Leadership Institute, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Farmworker law project training, 1996-1998 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Voceros training, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Rights training - Middletown, 1991-2004 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Statewide farmworker assembly, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Justice for farmworkers - Washington, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Farmworker Advocacy Coalition, 2001-2003 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Drivers licenses advocacy (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Joint legislative task force on farmworkers, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Farmworker hearings, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Immigration updates, 2007-2008 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Immigration training - University of Rochester, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Agriculture jobs - immigration bill (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Agriculture jobs - immigration bill, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Agriculture jobs - immigration bill, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Mexican consul, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Guestworker program, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- H2A guestworker training, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Legal - farmworker rights (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Citizenship questions guide (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Farmworker rights brochures (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Legal immigration, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Immigration training, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Immigration law training, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Immigration reform, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Amnesty of undocumented immigrants, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Immigrant amnesty petition (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Padre Alejandro-immigration, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Labor camp visitation rights, 1991-2004 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Immigration rights, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Individual taxpayer identification number (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Domestic violence training, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Codes of conduct toward farm labor, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Agricultural affiliates, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- New York State Farm Bureau, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- New York State Horticultural Society, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Onion farming in New York State, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Brightly Farm, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Dagele Farm organizing, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Hudson Valley Foie Gras AGY, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Lamont Farm, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Mortellaro and Sons Farm, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Don Perry and Chris Pawelski, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- M&M produce farms and sales, 1996-1999 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Shuback Farms, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Farmworker/Mexican jargon, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Immigration fingerprinting issue, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Money order problems, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Shooting at farmworkers - Kenall, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Slavery in New York State, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Human trafficking, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- New York State Defenders Association, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Rural Opportunities, Inc., 2003-2005 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Labor-religion coalition - NewYork State, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Rural and Migrant Ministry, 2001-2005 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Migrant coalition mailing lists (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Wayne County New York State Coalition of Farmworker Services, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- New York State Migrant Education Diversity Project, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Brockport Ecumenical Outreach Committee, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Working Together Group, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Gonzalez, Albino - died 1998, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Pesticides - project access, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Farmworker safety, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Migrant farmworker health, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Worker protection advocacy - New York State DEC, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Mow, Carolyn - miscellaneous, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Cornell, 1998-2001 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Cornell service - learning, 2004-2005 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Training needs of farmworkers in Orange and Sullivan Counties, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Interns - SUNY Brockport, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- University at Albany, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Latino/Puerto Rican directory - Michael Fondacaro, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- PACE - Proyecto de Trabajadores Agricolas, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Farmworker organizations - miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Correspondence, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Lobbying, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Lobbying, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Lobbying, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Lobbying, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Lobbying, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Lobbying, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Farmworker Advocacy Day, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Farmworker research - Cornell/NYSUT, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Lobbying, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Thomas Dorr controversy, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- State Senator Joseph Bruno, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- State senators correspomdence, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Rally march, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Farmworker Advocacy Day March, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Farmworker Advocacy Day March, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Farmworker Advocacy Day March, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Farmworker Advocacy Day March, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Farmworker Advocacy Day March, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Farmworker Advocacy Day March, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Farmworker Advocacy Day March, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Farmworker Advocacy Day March, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Justice for Farmworkers, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Justice for Farmworkers, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Justice for Farmworkers, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Justice for Farmworkers, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Farm organizing, 1999-2004 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- CITA presentations/delegations, 2001-2002 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Leadership Development Institute, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Latino Foods, Inc., 1995-2001 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Mexican independence event (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Community organizing training, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Farmworker law project - rent, 1997-1999 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Financial training (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Focus groups - training, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Project access, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Farmworkers Women Leadership Network - California, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Neighbors - Albion, New York, 2007-2008 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Clean Clothes and Fair Food Conference, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Unions - general, 2000-2003 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Union organizing, 2015 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Immigrant farmworker advocacy, 2000-2005 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Union organizing papers, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- La Red (Reunion El Paso) de Trabajadores Agricolas, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- AFL-CIO organizing immigrants, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- New York State - AFL-CIO, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Coalition of Immokalee workers, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- International factory workers union, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- La Union del Pueblo Entero (LUPE), 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- PCUN - Pineros y Campesinos Unides del Noroeste, 1998-2000 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- United Farm Workers (UFW), 2000 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Tribuno del Pueblo, 1996-1999 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Media coverage - farmworkers, 2004-2010 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Media coverage - farmworkers, 1998-2003 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Media coverage - farmworkers, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Soccer, 2005-2006 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Soccer, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Thank you letters, 2002-2008 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Support letters for grant proposals, 1996-1999 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Gifts, 1996-2003 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Fundraising - miscellaneous, 1994-2006 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Fundraising, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Grant proposals not funded, 1996-2005 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Grant proposals, 1998-2005 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Amanecer grant support - Chuck Barrett, 1996-2003 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- J. O'Connell and Associates - fundraising, 2004-2005 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Strategic planning - Anne Gardon, 2002-2003 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Abelard Foundation, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Ben and Jerry's Foundation, 1998-2006 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Catholic Campaign for Human Development, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Catholic Campaign for Human Development, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Catholic Campaign for Human Development, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Catholic Campaign for Human Development, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Catholic Campaign for Human Development, 1997-2001 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- CITA and Migrant Ministry (RMM) fundraising, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Discount foundation, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Crop Walk - Monroe, New York, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- United States Environmental Protection Agency, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Funding exchange, 1999-2005 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Genesee-Orleans (New York State) Regional Arts Council, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Harburg Foundation, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Jewish Fund for Justice, 1999-2002 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- New York State Office of Children and Family Services, 2005-2006 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Presbyterian fund, 1998, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Presbyterian women's fund, 1995,1998 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- La Union del Pueblo Entero (LUPE), 2002-2003 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- TSC Foundation, 2002-2005 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Rochester Area Community Foundation, 2005-2006 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- United Way - USA Patriot Act, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- CITA audit, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- CITA audit, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- CITA audit, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- CITA audit, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- CITA audit, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 37)
- CITA audit, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 38)
- CITA audit, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 39)
- CITA audit, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 40)
- CITA audit, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 41)
- CITA audit, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 42)
- CITA audit, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 43)
- CITA tax, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- CITA tax, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- CITA tax, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- CITA tax, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- CITA tax, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- CITA cash log, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- CITA cash log, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- CITA cash log, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- CITA cash log, 1998-1999 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- CITA budget, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- CITA tax return, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- New York State tax, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- CITA tax return, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- CITA flag (Box 6, Folder 14)
- T-shirt (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Justice for Farmworkers, 2004-03; DVD-1978 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- March for Justice-Nancy Ghertner Productions, 2004-03; DVD-1979 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- 330 Miles Toward Justice -production of Rural and Migrant Ministy and CITA, 2004; DVD-1980 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- 330 Miles Toward Justice, 2004; DVD-1981 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- 330 Miles Toward Justice, 2003; DVD-1982 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- March for Justice - Seneca Falls to Albany - Rural and Migrant Ministry, 2004; DVD-1983 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- March to Albany - Seneca Falls to Albany, CD-3255 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- 330 Miles Toward Justice, CD-3256 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- 330 Miles Toward Justice, CD-3257 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Discussion guides for DVDs (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Photos from "LaCena", 2004-03-02; CD-3258 (Box 6)
- Photos of cows and farms, CD-3259 (Box 6)
- Photos - Cancun, Sodus, fundraising, 2003-09; CD-3260 (Box 6)
- Immigration messaging forum and communications summit, 2008; CD-3261 (Box 6)
- Photos - soccer, Kendall, Labor Day Parade, 2003-07-2003-09; CD-3262 (Box 6)
- "Sweating for a T-Shirt", 1998; CD-3263 (Box 6)
- CIW uncensored (Box 6)
- Farmworkers (Box 6)
- Roots of Migration, a film by Mikel Barton, 2009; DVD-1986 (Box 6)
- Qien Dijo Miedo, DVD-1987 (Box 6)
- United Farmworkers - Spanish version, DVD-1988 (Box 6)
- The Fence - R. Kennedy, 2010; DVD-1989 (Box 6)
- La Americana - producer Nicholas Bruckman, 2008; DVD-1990 (Box 6)
- Strangers No Longer - funded by Catholic Communications Campaign and University of Notre Dame, DVD-1991 (Box 6)
- CITA photos, DVD-1992 (Box 6)
- Engre Nos, 2010; DVD-1993 (Box 6)
- The Visitor - Overture Films, 2008; DVD-1994 (Box 6)